Now that you know a simple way to solve the data association
现在 你已经掌握了解决数据关联问题的
problem, I'll go over the quiz.
简单方法 我们来看一下小测试
And you'll learn about some of the advantages
你会了解最近邻方法的
and disadvantages of the nearest neighbor technique.
一些优势和劣势
We'll come back to this.
我们后面会再讨论
Nearest neighbor is great, because it's
最近邻方法很好 因为
easy to understand and implement.
它易于理解和实现
Just take the closest measurement.
以最近测量值为例
Here, we are showing the association between the closest
这里 我们用红色圆圈显示了
lidar measurement and each map landmark with the red circles.
最近的激光雷达和每个地图路标之间的关联
However, simple techniques have some disadvantages
但是 简单的方法也有一些劣势
in that they are not as robust to difficult scenarios.
比如 它们应付困难场景时性能不佳
For instance, a high density of measurements
例如 如果测量值密度过高
would make this technique very prone to errors,
该方法就很容易出错
because one map landmark could be really
因为这时候地图地标
close to multiple measurements.
可能与多个测量值非常临近
It's unclear which feature in this image
我们无法确定图像中哪个特征
corresponds to these map landmarks.
对应这些地图地标
In addition, the nearest neighbor algorithm
此最近邻算法
is quite inefficient, because for each landmark
非常低效 因为对于每个地标
you have to search through all of the measurements
你必须彻底搜索所有测量值
to find the one with the minimum distance.
才能找到最短距离的那个值
Therefore, the complexity is O of mn,
因此 复杂度是 mn 分之 O
where m is the number of map landmarks
其中 m 是地标数量
and n is the number of sensors measurements.
N 是传感器测量值的数量
If there are a lot of sensor measurements, or landmarks,
如果有很多传感器测量值或地标
nearest neighbor could become quite slow.
最近邻可能非常慢
Additionally, if a sensor is very noisy,
此如果某个传感器非常嘈杂
you could easily match a spurious feature,
你就很容易匹配到假特征
one that doesn't actually correspond
假特征实际上不会把
to any object in the real world to a map landmark.
现实世界中的任何对象和地图地标对应起来
The landmark on the right has an incorrect association
右侧的地标由于传感器噪
due to sensor noise.
出现关联错误
You can tell that this other match is correct,
你可以看出 另一个匹配是正确的
because it matches the geometry of this other landmark match.
因为它匹配了这边另一个地标匹配的图形
Another disadvantage of nearest neighbor
最近邻的另一个劣势
is that it is not as robust to errors in the vehicle position
是它在车辆位置估算时
estimate.
容错稳健度不高
If the vehicle position has some errors,
如果车辆位置有些误差
nearest neighbor will also incur some errors.
最近邻也会产生误差
Here, the car is shifted to the right.
在这里 车辆偏移到了右边
So the measurements are also shifted to the right,
因此 测量值也偏移到了右边
as shown with the purple lines.
如红色线条所示
However, nearest neighbor will not see this pattern,
但是 最近邻不会看到这个图案
and will pick some incorrect correspondences,
它会挑选一些错误的对应
which are circled in black.
就是黑色圈出的部分
Another disadvantage of nearest neighbor
最近邻的另一个劣势
is that it does not take uncertainties of the sensor
是它不考虑传感器的
into account.
不确定性
For example, let's say you have a radar sensor that
例如 假设你有一个雷达传感器
has very precise bearing measurements and not
它分方位测量非常准确
as precise range measurements.
但没有测距仪的准确
The green ovals here represent the uncertainties
这里的绿色椭圆代表距离
in the range and bearing dimensions
这些雷达测量值的
for these radar measurements.
距离和方位值的不确定性
Nearest neighbor would pick this match,
最近邻会选择这个匹配
but this other match is more likely
但另一个匹配可能性更高
given that the sensor is very accurate in the bearing
因为传感器方位测量非常准确
dimension and not as accurate in the range dimension.
而距离大小测量不怎么准确
So let's summarize.
我们总结一下
The nearest neighbor data association technique
最近邻数据关联法
is easy to understand and implement,
易于理解和实现
and it works well in many situations.
在很多情况下效果很好
However, it is not as robust to large densities
但是 它对于高密度的测量值
of measurements, sensor noise, or errors
传感器噪或位置估算误差
in position estimates.
稳健度欠佳
It can be inefficient to compute,
它计算效率低下
and also does not take sensor uncertainties into account.
而且不会考虑传感器的不确定性
Now that you know how to associate the sensor
现在 你已经知道了如何将
measurements you get with landmarks in the map, next
传感器测量值和地图地标相关联
you'll learn how to implement the update step of the particle
接下来 你要学习如何在粒子滤波器中
filter.
实现更新步骤